Safeer PS

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER

Karama, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

■ 971561483175

Safeerps11@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/safeer-ps-342b8722/



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly dedicated and focused ICT Support Engineer with more than 4 years' extensive experience providing high level systems support and network maintenance. Possess strong technical knowledge and proficiency in system administration, networking, hardware maintenance and operating systems. Successful track record of providing assistance to end users and resolving technical issues that have eluded resolution by others.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

- Expert in configuring Microsoft 2008/2012 server, Active Directory, Group Policy, DNS, DHCP and file servers.
- Expert in configuring Fortinet Firewall (180 Outlets, FortiManager)
- Expert in configuring & Trouble Shooting Cisco IP Phones
- Expert in managing Cisco Call Manager
- Expertise in MS Office 365 and Exchange online administration using Admin portal.
- Expert in troubleshooting & configuration of Microsoft windows XP, windows 7, windows 8 and windows 10.
- Experience in VPN, LAN and WAN troubleshooting, administration and configurations.
- Experience in Troubleshooting, installation and configuration of desktops, laptops, printers and scanners.
- Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R2

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LIFE HEALTH CARE GROUP, DUBAI, UAE

April 2016 - PRESENT

IT & ERP SUPPORT ENGINEER

- Managing and Configuring Fortinet Firewalls
- Managing and Configuring Cisco IP Phones (180 Outlets and Corporate Office)
- Managing Cisco Call Manager
- Managing and configuring Active Directory, Office 365 and Exchange online in 500+ user's infrastructure environment.
- Technical Support for ERP (Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012R2)
- Monitoring and Managing Windows Server 2012 R2
- ERP Training for new Staff's (Pharmacy)
- IT Procurement
- Managing Malwarebytes and Cloud based Sophos antivirus solution for end points and servers.

- Setup equipment (surface pro, I pad, printers, scanners) with required application for End user, ensuring proper installation of operating systems and necessary software.
- IT infrastructure implementation for new stores,
- Preparing AX store Servers, POS Machines installed with Microsoft Dynamics AX modules for the new store opening.
- Providing remote technical support for Microsoft dynamics AX (Retail) to 180 + Pharmacies.
- Providing Technical support to All stores POS machines (HP RP 7800,HP RP 9 G1,Posiflex)Receipt printer, cash drawer, Barcode scanners and back office system.
- Raid configuring and setup for entry level store servers and POS machines.

EKK GROUP

MARCH 2015 - MAY 2016

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER

- Respond to IT incidents and requests received from LANDesk tickets escalated from the Service Desk.
- Administration of windows server 2018 Active directory (Added, maintained and removed objects within Active Directory).
- Creating new e-mails, User mailbox and Distribution Groups etc. using exchange management console).
- Installation and configuration of Node endpoint protection using endpoint protection manager console.
- Configured new desktops, software upgrades, problem solving both hardware and operating system issues and ensuring client application functionality.
- Configuring and troubleshooting printers, finger print readers, and scanners etc.
- Setup & maintain IT infrastructure at stores like network, voice and datainstallation
- Asset management of all IT equipment's.
- Scheduled Backup of database server at HO, stores and ware house.
- Handling around 11 store Servers 10 Application Servers including
- Monitoring connectivity of store servers to HO which is connected through IP-VPN.
- Installation, Configuration & Maintenance of CCTV (IP)

KAIZEN IT SERVICE- BANGALORE, INDIA

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2013

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ENGINEER

- Providing first level technical support to customers.
- Raising & maintaining incident tickets and problem records.
- Undertaking analysis, diagnosis and resolution of client problems via phone, e-mail & face to face contact.
- Designing, implementing and managing all the IT requirements
- Regularly check, network access protection and hardware and software inventory.
- Prepare assets, track, report containing updated locations of IT equipment and software installed in workstations, at concerned locations.
- Attend to all requests coming via telephone, emails, web or any other means and make sure that all requests are received and appropriate actions are initiated according to the business rules, policies, procedures, and standards.
- Perform other related duties as requested.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting IBM lotus notes
- Technical and Voice co-ordination with Server Team and Network Team for all kinds of issues and

SAFEER PS Private & Confidential

activities.

To give entire Hardware related support for clients which includes,

- Reliance Capital- Bangalore
- HK-Toll Plaza- Reliance Project

MOULANA HOSPITAL, INDIA

MARCH 2011 – APRIL 2013

IT ASSISTANT

Provide Level 2 support and facilitate Level 1 support Hardware and. To provide Telephonic or remote support and communicate with internal and external interfaces to resolve and correct problems, recording incidents, providing resolution and closing requests and respond to service inquires and network issues and problems. To provide technical troubleshooting and corrective measures.

Responsible of Installing, Maintaining and troubleshooting various Operating Systems in Windows environment.

- Installing & configuring extra hospital devices, Scanners and Printers etc.
- Responsible for providing efficient Technical support nursing student labs
- Support and Maintenance of LAN and server room

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Diploma in Electronics and Communication : SIVT

Higher secondary education : Educational Board Gov. of Kerala – India.
 Metric Education (SSLC) : Educational board Gov. of Kerala- India.

DECLARATION

The above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I am liable to be disqualified if any information given above is found incorrect/incomplete or false.

Sincerely Safeer PS

SAFEER PS Private & Confidential